{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Creedence Clearwater Revival","incorrectAnswers":["Johnny Cash","Elvis Presley","Al Green"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'Proud Mary', which was later covered by Ike and Tina Turner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Track and field","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Figure skating","Swimming"],"question":"With which sport is Wilma Rudolph associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harold II","incorrectAnswers":["William the Conqueror","Alfred the Great","Edward the Confessor"],"question":"What was the name of the last Anglo-Saxon king of England?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Czech Republic","USA"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Venice?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"3","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","4"],"question":"How many astronauts manned each Apollo flight?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Shark","Snake","Flower"],"question":"A Jacaranda is a type of what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isaac","incorrectAnswers":["Albert","Herbert","Luigi"],"question":"What was the first name of the physicist Newton?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Stringed","Brass","Percussion"],"question":"What type of instrument is a clarinet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","Southeast Asia","The Middle East"],"question":"From which part of the world do persimmons originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Harvard","incorrectAnswers":["Yale","Cornell","Princeton"],"question":"Which University, founded in 1636, is the oldest in the USA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frances McDormand","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Margot Robbie","Saoirse Ronan"],"question":"Who won the 2017 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Mildred in Three Billboards outside Ebbing, Missouri?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rattlesnake","incorrectAnswers":["Coyote","Goose","Pig"],"question":"The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Cursed Child'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cuba Libre","incorrectAnswers":["Mojito","Pina Colada","Daiqiri"],"question":"Which Cocktail contains rum, the juice of 1/2 a lime, and cola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"G. W. F. Hegel","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Whatever is reasonable is true, and whatever is true is reasonable'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Black","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Ecuador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"500","incorrectAnswers":["Camry","Phantom","Clio"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Fiat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Pierce Brosnan","George Lazenby","Roger Moore"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Thunderball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Horse","incorrectAnswers":["Bull","Elephant","Penguin"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Porsche logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Evangeline Lilly","incorrectAnswers":["Scarlett Johansson","Natalie Portman","Hayley Atwell"],"question":"Who plays the role of Hope Van Dyne in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oman","incorrectAnswers":["Cabo Verde","Belize","Timor-Leste"],"question":"Muscat is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Orleans","incorrectAnswers":["Miami","Los Angeles","Chicago"],"question":"Which US city is known for its voodoo rituals and voodoo queen Marie Laveau's tomb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Witness for the Prosecution'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Cambodia","Laos"],"question":"Which country's currency is the baht?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Yankee","incorrectAnswers":["Yearly","Yum","Yurt"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter Y?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stuart Little","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Little","Jack Little","Henry Little"],"question":"What is the name of E.B. White's adventurous mouse-like boy from a 1945 story?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Haitian Revolution","incorrectAnswers":["Liberian Revolution","American Revolution","French Revolution"],"question":"What was the name of the major uprising led by Toussaint L'Ouverture in the 18th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cathedral","incorrectAnswers":["Chapel","Spire","Oratory"],"question":"What type of Catholic church is the home church of a bishop?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rocky Mountains","incorrectAnswers":["Transantarctic mountains","Andes","Himalayas"],"question":"Which mountain range does the Colorado River flow through?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Radii","incorrectAnswers":["Radies","Radiusses","Radiants"],"question":"What is the plural of \"radius\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Joule","Pascal","Ohm"],"question":"What Is The SI Unit Of Force","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Thanos","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen Strange","Odin","T'Challa"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Josh Brolin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Clarence","incorrectAnswers":["Terrence","Horace","Boris"],"question":"In the 1946 film, It's a Wonderful Life, what's the name of George Bailey's guardian angel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Timisoara","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Amsterdam","Prague"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Romania?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sun Ra","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","Frank Zappa","June Tyson"],"question":"Which Keyboard Player Had An \"Arkestra\" & Claimed To Have Come From Another Planet\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Thirteen Problems'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Potato dumplings","incorrectAnswers":["Raw beef","Pickled turnip","Carrot sauce"],"question":"What is gnocchi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hippopotamus","incorrectAnswers":["Elephant","Rhinoceros","American Bison"],"question":"Which Is The Second Heaviest Land Animal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Spiderman","incorrectAnswers":["Obadiah Stane","Iron Man","Hawkeye"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Tom Holland?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Carpenters","incorrectAnswers":["The Black Keys","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American vocal duo released the studio album 'A Song for You'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Volleyball","Boxing","Table tennis"],"question":"With which sport is Joe DiMaggio associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Familiar","incorrectAnswers":["Totem","Mascot","Spirit guide"],"question":"What term refers to an animalistic spirit who aids a witch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Kareem Abdul-Jabbar","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jordan","Yao Ming","Kobe Bryant"],"question":"Who was the NBA MVP in 1976, 77, and 80?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Battle of Little Bighorn","incorrectAnswers":["Battle of Gettysburg","Battle of Cold Harbor","Battle of Stones River"],"question":"In which battle was George A. Custer defeated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Twilight","His Dark Materials","Red Rising"],"question":"In which book series does 'Minerva McGonagall' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cloud","incorrectAnswers":["Planet","Island","Volcano"],"question":"Cirrus and Cumulus are types of what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"8","incorrectAnswers":["5","14","20"],"question":"How many fighters are playable in 'Street Fighter II'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gloria","incorrectAnswers":["Lucy","Sally","Mary"],"question":"Which popular name for girls was sung about by Van Morrison, The Doors, U2, and Laura Branigan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tarawa","incorrectAnswers":["Tbilisi","Bissau","Ngerulmud"],"question":"What is the capital city of Kiribati?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"4 Calling Birds","incorrectAnswers":["4 Turtle Doves","4 French Hens","4 Drummers Drumming"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the fourth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Buddenbrooks","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does 'Marmee March' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Hyperbole","incorrectAnswers":["Metaphor","Simile","Personification"],"question":"What is the term for an exaggeration that uses extreme words and expressions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Windmills and similar devices","incorrectAnswers":["Plant communities","Massage","The earth's atmosphere"],"question":"What is Molinology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A dirigible","incorrectAnswers":["A helicopter","A heliomass","An aeroflot"],"question":"What is another name for an airship or blimp?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Ozarks","incorrectAnswers":["The Rockies","The Appalachians","The Andes"],"question":"Which heavily forested mountain range extends southward through Missouri from St. Louis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pork ","incorrectAnswers":["Chicken","Beef","Turkey"],"question":"What Type Of Meat Usually Goes Into Frankfurters?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montevideo","incorrectAnswers":["Bogotá","Zagreb","Bandar Seri Begawan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Uruguay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oscar Wilde","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","G. K. Chesterton","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Importance of Being Earnest'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Amphibian","incorrectAnswers":["Reptile","Fish","Mollusc"],"question":"What is a Salamander ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"High Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Impressionism","Mannerism"],"question":"The painting \"The Triumph of Galatea\" by Raphael is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eminem","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Drake","Ludacris"],"question":"Which American rapper, producer and actor released the song 'Lose Yourself'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The History of Middle-earth'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Let it Be\" by the Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["\"Man! I Feel Like a Woman!\" by Shania Twain","\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"When I find myself in times of trouble, Mother Mary comes to me / Speaking words of wisdom, let it be...\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cirrhosis","incorrectAnswers":["Hepatitis","Scurvy","Meningitis"],"question":"Which Disease Of The Liver Is Associated With Alcoholism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Washington DC","incorrectAnswers":["New York City","Brussels","Geneva"],"question":"Where is Capitol Hill?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Palau","Palestine","Portugal"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.pl' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Virgil Grissom ","incorrectAnswers":["Yuri Gagarin","Alan Shepard","Neil Armstrong"],"question":"Who was the first man to go to space twice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stephen Hawking","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Issac Newton","Richard Feynman"],"question":"Which physicist caused a stir in 2014 when he retracted his 1974 theory about black holes, stating that light may be able to escape them after all?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Suriname","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","Serbia","Sierra Leone"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sr' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Spotlight","incorrectAnswers":["The Big Short","Bridge of Spies","Brooklyn"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2015?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dutch ","incorrectAnswers":["German","Danish","French"],"question":"What Nationality Is The Lager Giant Grolsch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Dravidian","Koreanic"],"question":"The language 'Spanish' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Little ears","incorrectAnswers":["Little ribbons","Small thimbles","Butterflies"],"question":"The pasta orecchiette has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Dipthong","incorrectAnswers":["Kakorrhaphiophobia","Grommet","Jentacular"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'two vowel sounds joined in one syllable to form one speech sound, e.g. the sounds of “ou” in out and of “oy” in boy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Immanuel Kant","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Protagoras"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Happiness is not an ideal of reason but of imagination'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Enlightenment","incorrectAnswers":["The Reformation","The Renaissance","The Industrial Revolution"],"question":"The 18th century was the age of which major philosophical movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Salman Rushdie","incorrectAnswers":["Henry James","Brandon Sanderson","Vladimir Nabokov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Satanic Verses'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Buddenbrooks","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does 'Amy March' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frances McDormand","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Weisz","Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Transformers: Dark of the Moon and Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Aung San Suu Kyi","incorrectAnswers":["Kim Jong-un","Ho Chi Minh","Xi Jinping"],"question":"Which political leader played a major role in Myanmar's transition from a military junta in the 2010s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lolita","incorrectAnswers":["Gone With the Wind","The Thin Man","Henderson the Rain King"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Humbert Humbert'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bonnie Parker","incorrectAnswers":["Ma Baker","Anne Bonny","Mary Surratt"],"question":"Who was the first woman to be shot by the FBI?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Every man is the maker of his own fortune","incorrectAnswers":["Nothing is arduous for the fortunate","A beard doesn't make one fortuitous","One swallow does not make summer"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Faber est suae quisque fortunae' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"War and Peace","incorrectAnswers":["Anna Karenina","The Brothers Karamazov","Crime and Punishment"],"question":"Which novel by Leo Tolstoy was published in separate parts from 1865 to 1869?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Croatia","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Australia","Czech Republic"],"question":"In which country would you find the Plitvice Lakes National Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pepper","incorrectAnswers":["Chilli Powder","Cumin","Paprika"],"question":"What spice is used to cover steak in steak au poivre?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Nobel Peace Prize","incorrectAnswers":["A Grammy Award","The Pulitzer Prize","An Academy Award"],"question":"Which award did Martin Luther King win in 1964?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cronut","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Dosant","Chouxnut"],"question":"What is the name given to the pastry that looks like a doughnut, but made with choux pastry?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Severn ","incorrectAnswers":["The Thames","The Tee","The Mersey"],"question":"Which Is The Longest River In Britain","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Crete ","incorrectAnswers":["Corfu","Santorini","Rhodes"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Of The Greek Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Kenya","Tanzania","Sri Lanka"],"question":"Berber is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Baroque","incorrectAnswers":["Neoclassicism","Surrealism","Suprematism"],"question":"The painting \"Night Watch\" by ‎Rembrandt van Rijn is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eggplant ","incorrectAnswers":["Zucchini","Cilantro","Squash"],"question":"What do Americans call an Aubergine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Knight Rider","incorrectAnswers":["Airwolf","The A-Team","Hawaii Five-O"],"question":"Which 1980s adventure show featured a talking car named KITT?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ridley Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Gladiator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mercedes-Benz","incorrectAnswers":["Audi","BMW","Volkswagen"],"question":"What is the name of the German car brand whose logo is a three-pointed star?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Colombia","Chile","Panama"],"question":"In which country is the city of Quito?","difficulty":"medium"},